Stephen Warren Collection, 1855-1929
Roanoke Public Libraries
Roanoke Public Libraries
Stephen Warren Collection, 1855-1929
Roanoke Public Libraries
2011.12.2
4 Hollinger storage boxes
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Stephen Warren.
Introduction
The Stephen Warren Collection is a collection of photographs, correspondence, scrapbooks, and miscellaneous items of the Bryant, Mullins, Caldwell, and McManaway families.
Scope and Content
The collection contains a total of 4 storage boxes. The Bryant/ Mullins Series contains a notebook, a ledger, and tax receipts. The Caldwell Series contains mainly photographs and a few small miscellaneous items. The McManaway Series contains photographs, church bulletins, correspondence, and a teacher’s grade book. The Local Photographers and Scrapbook Series contains miscellaneous photographs, papers, and other small items.
Arrangement
3 boxes arranged by surname. 1 box contains miscellaneous items.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Index Terms
Roanoke, Virginia
Contents List
- Bryant/ Mullins Series (Franklin County), 1855-1904. (Box 1)
  - Notebook 1-Poems, 1855 letter by John Bryant, 1855. (Folder 1)
  - Book 2- 1871ledger for John Bryant, 1871. (Folder 2)
  - Franklin Co. Tax Receipts, 1891-1904. (Folder 3)
- Caldwell Series (Box 2)
  - Caldwell Family (Folder 1)
  - Caldwell Family Photographs (Folder 2)
  - Roanoke Caldwell Family Photographs (Folder 3)
  - Photographs [Caldwell family or local photographer, most unidentified]. (Folder 4)
  - Photographs [Caldwell family or local photographer, most unidentified]. (Folder 5)
  - Photographs [Caldwell family or local photographer, most unidentified]. (Folder 6)
- McManaway/ Wright Series, 1926-1936. (Box 3)
  - Berta McManaway (Chamblisburg, VA): Teacher photograph and "The Teachers Model Pocket Register and Grade Book" for New Hope School, 1875-1886. (Folder 1)
  - Mrs. Wright: Autograph book with student names. Roanoke, VA. School unidentified. (Folder 2)
  - Letters to Paul Wright. Additional letters to McManaway family, Sunday school book, and Roanoke Club letter. (Folder 3)
  - John W. McManaway's letters to his sisters Mabel and Eliza(Notes created by donor, Stephen Warren), 1918-1929. (Folder 4)
  - Maggie McManaway's family letters. (Folder 5)
  - First Baptist Church in Roanoke, VA attended by Billy McManaway. (Folder 6)
  - McManaway family papers (in green notebook). (Folder 7)
- Local Photographers and Scrapbook Series, 1884-1920's. (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1920's. Salem, Blacksburg, Welsh W.VA., Lakeside locations identified. Other photos, 1920's. (Folder 1)
  - Photo of Lizzie E. Fishburn, Roanoke, VA, December 1897. (Folder 2)
  - J.M. Bennett and Laura B. Loving: Payment receipts, 1921. (Folder 3)
  - Warren C. Parsell dog tag. (Folder 4)
  - William Dooly (Chamblisburg, VA) Account expenses with J.F. Thaxton, 1884-1887. (Folder 5)
  - Lakeside Park ticket stubs (Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Roanoke area, Lexington, Salem, and Lynchburg. (Folder 7)